Hello, welcome to the next episode of Learn German in Hindi.
Today we are going to
learn the important
forms of adjectives. This concept is
exactly like English, that is why we are going to
learn it with the help of English.
Meaning, look, which is cheap, which thing
can be tipped only, which ad is cheap, which is
cheaper than HC, which thing will be
given, this is the cheapest, which cheese
paste is chips on cheese or all, what is a very simple
decrement? When you say cheap, it is a
positive degree, both are equal right, when you are
saying that one thing is better than the other, then it is a
comparative degree and which is the third one, if you
take super, that is the best, if it is MS
Word, then it is positive, if it is exam, then it is
comparative, it is tasty, then
taking super concept, all these are chakli shampoo in German,
if you are asked to say this thing
in German, it is called billi or
cat, in which area you are living, then
chief, if you say cheese,
put stock in German also, billi ghar and here you had
applied cheese paste, put mango there,
in the beginning and at the end match span a  Billi
Eastern So what was the first thing you had to do, what
thing should we not eat, add
in German which and we should put that strobe
English BP C which job liquid scene
that similarly if you want to say which thing then
you should concentrate on in German, all
cockpit digger and on this earth it is so easy, what cheese
paste which common
electronic see it is very simple that
where there was s.st there job grand chirwa
chip paste now electronics such testing is done taking
tasty meaning so we do
weekly which tasty which taking which
add test years on which
also tips ee ee
12 taking taisee which tasty arghya
taking playlist all spheres which chest which
system taking turn on in this very simple nothing
is there, nothing is there
yet in English if
you must have seen when you do costly
and what do you do for real, when you clear the cost then what do you do while doing the
final year of friendly  I do IR, I
hope so there is an option, it is a bigger thing than that,
what do you do with important, you
don't do important, you were doing more important, you do
most important, so
Lucky Ali, it is not that regular in German,
what happens in German, sometimes you will
always use a little Europe, love and stand, there will be a
little change in the form, so what
happens, the gang is Ras, meaning big Gurusar
Angiras, turn off, one locked, look, star swam, mango,
check return, again age,
and there are some other few words that I have
changed a little and asked the meaning of festival, mango, yoga,
stand, so Agyeya changed a little, but
look, these are a few,
I have given you a list of some of these here,
as you use it, you will come to know it,
it is part and parcel of any language, answer,
why learn a language, with its exception,
what is the basic, you have to
remember that it will seem air
and we will seem stunt, concept year to everyone, now
you will not keep saying good-good Arunesh,
good-good, update your moral, moral
modest  We don't say theorems here the
regular thing is exactly the same in German as well similarly
which is the regular team look
goodbye effect mango wiston good better mango
western
means my friend lot of I now Michael
Meyer means scenic spot means most and is a
typical German style this non non means
yellow liver means more yellow mango
list is very much yellow for now we do
n't need it so much first two
are more important agni and gutkha let's try it once again I will
use perfect but in factory I
use vinod and bread were we do
n't have to use der das these days we have to use
Ajmer region ok it is simple then for this
good for this cute which city DSC
cast your vote whip sea which better than
kidney which twist simple tips this
paste system western Sydney there
is no change still remember like this
Simra right now let me tell you one small thing different
now see what we are learning that
when adjective is different then we are seeing that
when good bye when  Goodbye, those who can become are
never learning that executive
and doing, this is that given concept because
when in the mind, like in Hindi, the
adjective that comes before Nautanki nine changes a little,
that is us too, those who see in va, don't worry, I want not right now,
they are focusing,
adjectival form, so the adjectival form is
understood by everyone, add is a very simple concept, normal is to use
care, now using stand is comparative, so friend,
superlative, mango and stand, there are
slight changes in very small places, it seems that there is a
change here and there and
sip and sesame change a lot
and how to use it is equal, then it
is ineffective or if it is more, well, with another thing, then
using is and we are, that
now taking the last name, stand, long list, simple
step, you have predictive above, so
making its form is very simple, I hope
you all have understood it from constructive,
we will meet in the next episode,
thank you